Guide to the Harvey Fierstein Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Topical, 1896-2005 (inclusive), 1967-2005 (bulk); Series III
  - Fierstein, Harvey
    - Congratulatory cards, 1982, 1985, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Financial, 1976-2002, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Professional correspondence, 1983-1996, undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Postcards to relatives, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Scrapbook, 1969-2001, undated (Box 48)
  - Freemasons, 1982, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Friends and Advocates for Individual Rights (FAIRPAC), 1987-1988 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Gay Day, Ridgefield, Connecticut, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Glines, 1980-1982, undated (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Gordon, Keith, undated (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - HBO, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Koutoukas, H. M., 1967-1972, undated (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Merrill, Helen, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Morris, William termination, 1992-1993 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Music, 1896, 1919-1976, undated (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Names Project, 1987-1990 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - O'Connor, Cardinal John, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Plays
    - She's Delovely by John Cassavetes, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - White Lies by Ken Selden, 1993 April 1 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Woody Allen '93, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Posters, 1999, undated (Box 50)
  - Rockefeller grant, 1978-1981 (Box 51, Folder 28)
  - Sedaris, David, 1992, undated (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Theatre memorabilia
    - General, 1964-1985, undated (Box 51, Folder 30 - 31)
    - Benefits, 2004-2005 (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - Pins and wristbands, 1983, undated (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - Programs, 1969-1986, undated (Box 51, Folder 34 - 35)
  - Veterans memorial, Ridgefield, Connecticut, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 36)
  - West, Mae [mostly photocopies of clippings], 1927-1928, 1982, undated (Box 51, Folder 37)
- Clippings, 1971-2005; Series IV
  - 1971-1983 (Box 52, Folder 1 - 9)
  - 1984-1988 (Box 53, Folder 10 - 18)
  - 1988-1995 (Box 54, Folder 19 - 28)
  - 1996-2002 (Box 55, Folder 29 - 38)
  - 2003-2005 and undated (Box 56, Folder 39 - 48)
- Audiovisual material, 1966-2004; Series V
  The series is arranged in three groups: Audio, Video, and Photographs. Audio and Video are arranged alphabetically by title. They primarily document productions in which Fierstein performed. Photographs are divided into three subgroups: Fierstein alone, Fierstein with others, and others. Most photographs are unidentified. Note that photographs may also be found in Series I and Series II.
  - Audio
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - La Cage aux Folles-last run through, 2004 (Box 57)
    - Freaky Pussy, undated (Box 58)
    - Hairspray-rehearsal, 2000 May (Box 59)
    - In Search of the Cobra Jewels-closing night, 1972 (Box 60)
    - My Foetus Lived on Amboy Street [7 1/2 ips; 1/4 track stereo; ], undated (Box 61)
    - 1010 WINS Radio-bits about Fierstein, 1995 June (Box 62)
  - Video
    - Fierstein, Harvey-interviews [excerpts from various television appearances; 4 tapes; ], 1993 November 14, undated (Box 63–66)
    - Haunted Host, 1991 May 24 (Box 67)
    - On Tidy Endings-rushes, days 1-10 [2 tapes; ], undated (Box 68–69)
    - Pouf Positive, 1991 May 24
      See: Series V. Audiovisual, 1966-2004 Box 67
    - Torch Song Trilogy
      - Cuts, undated (Box 70)
      - Feature [2 tapes; ], 1988 November 30 (Box 71–72)
      - Screening copy [2 tapes; ], 1988 September 6 (Box 73–74)
      - Television recordings [2 tapes; ], 1991 December 6, 9 (Box 75–76)
  - Photographs
    - Fierstein alone, 1966-1984, undated (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Fierstein with others, 1978-2002, undated (Box 77, Folder 2 - 3)
    - Others, 1971, undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
- Additional material, 1989-2006; Accession 2007-M-028
  - Printed materials
    - La Cage aux Folles reunion photo/poster, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Two copies.
    - Hairspray press kits and promotional items for Las Vegas production, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Articles about Harvey Fierstein, 1989 May 22, 2006 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Audiovisual
    - Broadway's Lost Treasures, 2006 June 6; 1 commercially produced videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
      Narrated by Fierstein; WNET/13.
    - Drama Desk Awards, 2006; 1 (Box 3)
      Hosted by Fierstein.
    - Hairspray production photographs for Las Vegas production, 2006 February; 1 (Box 4)
    - Happy Birthday Oscar Wilde, 2005; 1 commercially produced optical disk (DVD) (Box 5)
      Tribute in which Fierstein appears.
    - Today Show, 2006 May 31; 1 commercially produced optical disk (DVD) (Box 6)
      Katie Couric's final show with Fierstein as guest.
- Additional material, Accession 2008-M-073
  - Printed materials and photographs
    - A Catered Affair, 2004-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes programs, script drafts, and publicity material.
      - Poster, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Programs and promotional materials from various productions, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes La Cage aux Folles and Torch Song Trilogy.
    - Theater Hall of Fame induction program, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 60th annual Tony awards reunion photograph and letter, 2006 June 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Op-Ed pieces on gay marriage and prejudice, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Audiovisual files
    - A Catered Affair
      - Electronic press kit - commercial, Circa 2004-2008; 7; 6 computer files (DVD-Video), commerically produced (Box 3U)
        Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
      - Patron offer - commercial, Circa 2004-2008; 7; 6 computer files (DVD-Video), commercially produced (Box 4U)
      - Old Globe system rec, 2007 October 10; 15 computer files (WAV) (Box 5U–6U)
      - Theater talk, 2008 April; 7 computer files (DVD-Video) (Box 7U)
      - Live performance at Old Globe in San Diego, 2007 October 11; 16 (Box 8U–9U)
      - Live performance at Old Globe in San Diego, 2007 October 29; 17 (Box 10U–11U)
    - Hairspray, Las Vegas, B roll - commercial, 2006 February; 6 computer files (DVD-Video), commercially produced (Box 12U)
    - The Family Guy episode with Fierstein as guest - commercial, 2008 April 4; 7 computer files (DVD-Video), commercially produced (Box 13U)
    - A Year without Santa Claus - commercial, 2006; 10 computer files (DVD-Video), commercially produced (Box 14U)
- Additional material, 2008; Accession 2010-M-052
  - Printed materials, 2008
    - New Dramatists 59th Anniversary Spring Luncheon, 2008 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Seventy-Fourth Annual Drama League Awards, 2008 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The 53rd Drama Desk Awards, 2008 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A Musical Salute and 80th Birthday Celebration in Honor of Jerry Bock, 2008 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Box office advertisement for La Cage Aux Folles, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Audiovisual material
    - A Catered Affair [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 2)
    - Hairspray [Commercially produced], 2008 December 10- 11; 1 (Box 3)
    - Theater Talk, Harvey returns to close Hairspray [Commercially produced], 2008 December; 1 (Box 4)
    - Torch Song Trilogy
      - Death Scene, part 1 [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 5)
      - Death Scene conclusion, stoop scene [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 6)
      - Cemetery fight [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 7)
      - Front stoop, Brooklyn [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 8)
      - Ma's Arrival [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 9)
      - Ma's Arrival, beach scene [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 10)
      - Ed's apt, Alan's date (?), Laurel and Ed's lunch [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 11)
      - Alley scenes, Christopher St., Ext CLub, drunk scene, stair scenes [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 12)
      - Ed and I on the farm, Laurel's phone call, farm arrival, dinner, after dinner, fugue scores [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 13)
      - Farm bedroom, photographer's studio [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 14)
      - Picnic, outhouse, taxi [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 15)
      - Ma's house, opening, dinner, porch, shiva (sp?) [Commercially produced], 1 (Box 16)
- Additional material, 1970-2015; Accession 2017-M-0037; 4.93; (21 boxes)
  This addition consists primarily of scripts, programs, and other production materials from productions that Fierstein produced, wrote, or featured in as a performer. Also includes press clippings from these same productions and some of Fierstein's writings regarding a variety of topics, including theater and LGBTQ+ rights.
  This addition also contains legal and financial papers, contracts and press clippings and correspondence regarding the New Line lawsuit, when Fierstein sued New Line cinema for changes made to the Torch Song Trilogy when it was aired on television.
  Material in this addition ranges from 1970-2015, with the bulk of the material ranging between 1990 and 2010.
  Arrangement
  This addition is arranged in alphabetical order, with materials related to specific productions organized under the title of the production.
  The computer files are unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu. The request should outline the scope and purpose of the research project, why the researcher believes the material is relevant to their project, and contact information. If possible the request should also include a list of specific material of interest including collection, box, and folder numbers (or folder descriptions if folders are not numbered). The review may take several weeks.
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - An Affair to Remember: script, 2008 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Behind the Burly Q: correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Big Cutie in Little Italy: correspondence, contracts, and notes, 1999–2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Blonde Venus: event notes, correspondence, copyright information (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Casa Valentina
    - Script files, circa 2014; 1.0 (Reel 7)
    - Electronic press kit, circa 2014; 1.0 (Box 8)
    - Manhattan Theatre Club at the Samuel J. Friedman Theatre program, 2014 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Press clippings, 2014 April 20-30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Production photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Christopher at Sheridan Squared: H.M. Koutoukas flier, circa 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Common Ground: Main Street Project contracts and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contracts and business correspondence, 1991–1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Drama Desk Awards: hosted by Harvey Fierstein, 2011; 1 (Box 9)
  - Fiddler on the Roof
    - Contract, riders and budgets, 2004 December (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Greetings, circa 2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Harvey Fierstein as Tevye photographs (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Minskoff Theatre program, ticket and bookmark, 2006 January (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Reviews and press clippings, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Tour production contract and reviews, 2009–2010 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Freaky Pussy: Fortune Theatre flier, circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Funny Girl: Savoy program, circa 2015 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Garden Variety: budget, notes, press release, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hairspray
    - Hollywood Bowl correspondence and contracts, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Hollywood Bowl 90th season brochure, 2011 August 2-7 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Neil Simon Theatre program, 2009 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Harvey and Friends, 2008 April 1; 1.0 (Box 10)
  - Harvey Fierstein headshots (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Haunted Host
    - Actors' playhouse program, 1991 April (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - La Mama E.T.C. Theatre program, circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Special offer flier, circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Helen Hayes Theater anniversary gala, 2014; 1.0 (Box 11)
  - In Search of the Cobra Jewels: The Playwrights' Workshop Club inc. flier, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - In the Life: contracts and correspondence, 2003–2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Innovative Artists: conracts, correspondence, notes, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The International Stud
    - 5 original concept drawings for the setting, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Players Theatre flier, circa 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Press clippings, 1978 February (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Program, 1978 February 2-19 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - La Cage Aux Folles
    - Contracts and newspaper clips, 2003–2004 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Don Gregory production, 1993–1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Foreign licenses, 2003–2013 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Foreign licenses, 2003–2013 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Harry, Jerry Herman, Arthur Launets contact sheets, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Harvey Fierstein as "Albin" correspondence and contracts, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - International licenses correspondence and contracts, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Kennedy Center honors, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Live on Broadway, part 1 of 2, 2011 April; 1.0 (Box 12)
    - Live on Broadway, part 2 of 2, 2011 April; 1.0 (Box 13)
    - London production contract, correspondence, 2007–2009 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Longacre Theatre program, 2011 March (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Press clipping, 2011 April 29 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Legs Diamond script and scores PDF, 1.0 (Box 14)
  - Letter to Three Wives/Letter to Five Wives: correspondence, 2005–2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lionsgate: correspondence, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Little Match Girl Makes it Big: WPA Theatre flier (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Little Theater (Helen Hayes Theater) 85th anniversary photograph, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Low Life in High Heels: contracts and correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Madame La Gimp: correspondence and legal documents, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Mae West project: correspondence and contract (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous: Hischfeld drawing and prints (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The New Dramatists: 59th anniversary spring luncheon program, 2008 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - New Line Lawsuit
    - Press, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and clippings, 1991–1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Newsies
    - All scripts from start to Broadway, circa 2011; 1.0 (Box 15)
    - Complete files, circa 2011; 1.0 (Box 16)
    - Nederlander Theatre program, 2012 March (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Paper Mill playhouse program, 2011 September 15-October 16 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Reading, Spring 2011; 1.0 (Box 17)
  - Op-eds and newspaper articles written by Harvey Fierstein, 2013–2014 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Personal appearances: London and United Kingdom, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pinoti Papers and One Man's Religion, circa 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Queen of Greece flier, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Rescue Me: contract, correspondence and notes, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Saving Grace: correspondence and notes, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Secret Place: program (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Sissy Duckling: contract, correspondence and script, 1998–2000 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - St. Louis book festival brochure, 2013 November 3-17 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Theater Talk: Hairspray and La Cage Aux Folles, circa 2011; 1.0 (Box 18)
  - This is Not Going to Be Pretty
    - Fierstein with American Flag slides and negatives, circa 1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clips, 1998–1999 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Production, 1995; 1.0 (Box 19)
  - Those Two: CBS news and correspondence (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Tidy Endings: HBO showcase press release, 1988 July 29 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Tonight Show With Jay Leno: Harvey Fierstein, 2013 June 20; 1.0 (Box 20)
  - The Torch Song Trilogy
    - Actors' playhouse program, 1982 March (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Film press, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Foreign licenses, 1989–2013 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Leventhal correspondence and litigation, 1992–1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Leventhal correspondence and litigation, 1992–1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Widows and Children First program, circa 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - French production correspondence, 2005–2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Touchstone and ABC contracts, correspondence, press clippings (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Touchstone/Fox: correspondence and contract, 2005–2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Untitled Columbia pictures project correspondence and contract, 1993–1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - WNET Thirteen: Harvey Fierstein 50th anniversary taping, 1.0 (Box 21)